# **Prateek Singh Arora**



psarora2151@gmail.com [ LinkedIn: psarora2151 [ +1 (604) 999-0885 | Vancouver, BC

As someone with computing experience, I have been able to **will ideas into existence** through the **power of binary**. From integrating APIs to developing scripts that run 24/7, I have poked and prodded as deep as assembly architectures. I have experience with OOP, scripting and markup languages, as do I with small teams. The natural step forward is to do that as part of a larger collective.

I am a Creative, who is driven by the need to help the masses better understand the world and themselves. My **creative edge** is what **dictates my sense of purpose**, just as it did for those who have made strides in any industry.

## WORK EXPERIENCE

#### **iOS and FULL-STACK DEVELOPER**

Oswald Labs (Swift, Node, JavaScript)

Jan 2023 - April 2024

- Developed Shravan app for iOS built on the Oswald Labs Platform, globally recognized for accessible learning, leading to *expanding the customer-base* by 17,000 in four weeks following the launch
- Developed web accessibility tools and browser extensions for Chromium-based browsers to grow the user-base by 41%
- Designed a heuristically optimized user interface, increasing usability testing satisfaction rate by 23%

#### **MANAGER** at Peer Education for CS

FIC at Simon Fraser University (C++, Python, Java, Discrete Math)

Jan 2021 - Dec 2022

- Optimized the mentor-mentee pair-up process through automation scripts to manipulate CSV/XLSX files, resulting in the program being extended by an additional week for the same *cost of operation*
- Oversaw and designed the peer mentorship program enhancing structure and training, which resulted in a 37% increase in mentor sign-up rate
- Provided academic support and implemented improvements to operations, resulting in a 14.6% higher *mean grade* for students tutored by my team compared to the whole program's

# TECHNICAL PROJECTS

#### **REACT-BASED AI APPLICATION**

(React.JS, OpenAl API, Firebase API)

- Developed a React-based Al application to streamline academic research, resulting in a 92.7% course grade through innovative UI design and API integration
- Integrated OpenAl's API into React framework to implement an efficient academic paper retrieval system, resulting
  in a 400% increase in speed compared to the competing AI API
- Contributed to a dynamic software development team, using the **Kanban** model, a blend of **agile and DevOps** methodology, achieving a 20% faster *implementation of requirements* compared to other teams
- Wrote unit and integration tests to maximize the software quality and maintain the repository, and deployed using Netlify to automate continuous deployment from Git to reduce the manual testing time by 45%
- Code hosted on GitHub ☑

#### **ARTIFICIAL INTELLIGENCE IN PacMac**

(Python)

- Developed and implemented search algorithms for problem-solving and pathfinding, by creating intelligent agents for strategic game playing using AI concepts, like Markov Decision Processes (MDPs), Reinforcement Learning, Bayesian networks and Hidden Markov Models
- Code hosted on GitHub ☑

# TECHNICAL PROJECTS (contd.)

#### **PORTFOLIO WEBSITE**

(HTML, CSS, JS, Bootstrap)

- Developed and deployed a personal website using HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, and JavaScript to showcase projects to recruiters and peers
- Organized projects and skills—personal and professional—to boost online visibility and maximize **SEO optimization**, resulting in a 7% *increase in visitors* contacting through the website

### **SKILLS**

#### Languages

• Python, C/C++, C#, JavaScript, Java, HTML, Swift, SQL

# Web Technologies, Operating Systems, Testing & Frameworks

- · Bootstrap, React, Node, CSS, LaTeX
- · Object Oriented Programming, Figma, iOS, MacOS, Linux, Windows, Git
- · Usability Testing, Unit & Integration Testing, Docker, Yarn, NPM, Netlify

#### Other Relevant Skills

- Demonstrated proficient written and verbal communication skills through my personal NEWSLETTER (access here ☑) and creation of videos on YOUTUBE (access here ☑)
- · Discrete math concepts, team leadership, interpersonal teamwork, training development, problem solving

# **EDUCATION**

#### **Bachelor of Science in COMPUTER SCIENCE**

Simon Fraser University (SFU), Vancouver

Sept 2020 - current

Recipient of Community Engagement SCHOLARSHIP

# **INTERESTS**

- Drawing a self-invented style of art form, showcased on my portfolio website
- Writing, exploring and reading creative/philosophical ideas
- Improving and maintaining physical/mental well-being through resistance training, outdoor activities and basketball
- Editing videos to tell stories, communicate ideas, document life, and relating to others